Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
My name is Harrison.
I'm 40 years old.
I was among the 126 deportees last week from Libya.
We wanted to cross the mediterranean sea to Italy.
God saved me as I was not supposed to go home free.
I am supposed to come to His altar and thank Him very much.
It would be very bad for me to go home without thanking God.
So, I decided to thank God in this church.
We were 126 deportees last week.
The last two weeks and upper last week was almost 600 thanks to Prophet T.B. Joshua.
They gave us 7 million naira and two bags of rice each.
A big thanks to Pastor.
Mr Harrison
Libya Deportee Sharing Life Experience
The experience I had there - what my eyes have seen, I cannot put it into words.
I was working as a dock worker at Ibru Jetty where they have between 18 and 20 oil companies.
After some of the dock workers were registered as staff and I was not, I had to think of a way forward.
That was how I took the decision to go to Italy through Libya.
On our journey from Liby to Italy, we were almost 142 passengers who travelled
through the mediterranean sea in an inflatable boat.
When we were about to embark on the journey, it was discovered that the boat was leaking
and we decided to turn back.
They wanted to go again but 30 minutes into the journey,
it was discovered that there was not enough fuel, so we came back again.
My mind was telling me not to go.
I wanted to go back but I decided that as a man, I would take courage and go,
instead of staying in my country.
I was forced to embark on that journey.
The third time, when we passed Tunis, we got to another country before getting to Italy.
On getting to Malta, the boat started leaking again. People started screaming,
especially the girls among us. We were warned not to stand up and were told to squat.
Out of fear, the girls started standing on their feet, causing the boat to sink.
People were falling into the water, dying.
We were even seeing many whose boat had already capsized.
We were not even thinking about them; we were thinking about how to save our own lives.
There was a woman and a man who had a newborn baby there.
They held the baby up in their hands as the boat was sinking.
I was even thinking of what I could do -
turn by turn I would die so let me pray and ask God for forgiveness in case I died.
I was even looking at the woman; she held the baby in her hands but she sank with her husband.
I was running to the other side that was not in the water but unfortunately,
their boat sank on the other side and both of them died.
When the boat went down, I held onto a jerry can that had been full of fuel but was then empty.
The man who was controlling the boat held onto another jerry can.
I had a little experience of diving work when I was in Ibru Jetty, so I held the jerry can to my stomach.
Then, some criminals pulled their boat alongside ours
and started using their sticks on people who were trying to rescue themselves.
They struck people with their sticks to make them sink into the water.
They found three of us who were capable to make a move and took us into their boats.
They used their guns to hit our heads.
That is where I got this very big wound here; it tore, blood started coming out and I was unconscious.
When I opened my eyes in the night, I found myself in an underground prison.
We were three - myself, the captain of the boat and another boy; we were in the prison.
I thought we were in a hospital but we were in a prison.
It was as if we were watching a film.
They threw us inside an underground cell and closed the door.
When they closed it, the place was dark. We could not see anybody.
When they served us food, they would give us a thin slice of bread, half the size of my hand.
They would give us one slice of bread with a tiny amount of butter to eat.
In the afternoon, they would not give us any food.
In the evening, they would give us one particular type of food.
Most of my friends will be shouting now, "Ah, thank God that this boy is even giving his testimony
of what he experienced!"
They would bring a particular type of food.
It was just as if when one cooks beans in a pot and pours soap and water inside to wash them -
the mixture of water and soap was how the water which they served us at night looked like.
They would bring that together with a piece of bread.
That was the food we would eat 'til the following day.
After three days, inside our dark prison cell, when they had opened the door, trying to give us food,
we discovered that one of us was already dead.
We shouted in their language that someone had died in our midst.
After telling them that somebody had died, we were beaten with concrete pipes.
They would use that to flog us every day after bringing us out.
Whenever they wanted to feed us, they would throw us outside in the sun
and ask us to face its direction after eating.
They later took us to another location where we met not less than 10,000 Nigerians.
We were placed in different prisons. People were crying.
The worst treatment they gave to Nigerians was deceiving them that they had jobs for them in Italy.
After collecting some money from them, on getting to Benghazi or Tripoli,
they would stop the vehicle and ask those whose money was not complete to step down
before they were moved into three rooms.
Those three rooms which had only two ceilings harboured over 60 Nigerians.
There was no air or ventilation.
Men are strong but some of the women would have died before daybreak.
We would be escorted with guns to go and throw away their corpses in the desert.
We would dig shallow graves, put them inside and use our legs to cover the sand over them and go.
That day, I was even hungry, looking for food to eat.
I went to a place in Tripoli where we usually went in search for jobs.
My main aim for going to that place was to get a job so that I could get something to eat.
We were two in number - myself and a friend called Eze.
As we were looking for a job, a car parked beside us and the driver asked us to enter.
After we had entered the car, the driver brought out a gun and threatened to kill us if we talked.
We cooperated with him.
Then, he took us to a seaside and upon getting there, we found 52 dead bodies on the shore.
We were asked to load the 52 dead bodies into a truck.
By then, I was hungry and had no strength to even lift one of the dead bodies,
most of which were mutilated.
The clothes I wore that day were the ones I had worn for almost one year without changing.
I didn't even have enought money to eat, much less to buy clothes to change into.
Imagine a situation where someone would just call you to come and help him pump his tyres,
only for him to bring out a gun when you bend down to do so, shoot you and then drive off.
Some of them would ask me to come and help them start their generators
but before entering their house, they would hide all their female children and wives.
They would lock them inside a room.
Anything that made one see their wives,
they would make sure that the person did not come out alive.
Blacks don't see their wives with the naked eye.
In the market, the men normally sell okra, tomatoes and seasoning - that is man's work there.
Let me continue with my story.
So, they said we should pack the dead bodies - 52 dead bodies.
I was then weak - no food.
Now, I am even strong.
We were even looking for food when they told us to pack the dead bodies.
We were whipped and told to load the dead bodies into the truck. So we started to pack them.
52 dead bodies.
We offloaded the 52 dead bodies in the truck and took them to the desert where we buried them
in shallow graves - three bodies in one grave.
After burying the entire dead bodies, do you know what they gave us as compensation?
We were compensated with a piece of bread and a small portion of maccaroni.
They would force us to eat it and afterwards, ask us if it tasted nice.
We would have to agree that it tasted nice, otherwise, they would beat us to death.
They would pack us back into the vehicle, drop us off at the place they picked us from
and kick us out of the vehicle.
I could not even tell my story to anbody there. My whole body would smell of dead bodies.
When I would enter that place I stayed, there was no water to bath and nothing to use.
Before I could buy water, I would have to pass through another compound to fetch the water.
If I decided to narrate the whole ordeal I pass through in Liby, no one would go home today.
Ok, we know you have a lot of experiences to share with the people of God.
Because of time, we will just go straight to how you finally got back to Nigeria.
By the grace of God, I dreamt about Prophet T.B. Joshua that I came to this church
and he poured water on me.
When I woke up, I told my friends that I dreamt about Prophet T.B. Joshua.
In the prison there, we were almost 10,000 Nigerians
and even as we were leaving, we left about 7,000 there.
People are still there suffering.
I told my friend that I had dreamt of Prophet T.B. Joshua.
He replied excitedly that we would still go back home by the grace of God.
Fortunately for us, the next day, we heard that the UN started compiling the list of prisoners.
We started jubilating saying, "We are going home!"
Ten days later, we were moved to Tripoli in preparation for going home.
As I speak, many people in the Libyan prisons are wishing to come to The SCOAN
and give testimony about their experiences.
When we came here, T.B. Joshua compensated us with the sum of 7 million naira
and two bags of rice each. We thank God for that.
So, on coming back home...
The man of God said we should go back to our homes.
Unfortunately for me, when I got home, I became so sad as the only child I had
and was hoping to come home and meet (a boy), had died.
I had no home to stay, no house - nothing.
My wife even got married to another person because everybody thought that I was dead.
Even when I got to my compound,
some people picked up sand and threw it at me to confirm if I was truly alive.
I then told them that I was not dead, that I had spent five years in Libya,
three of which I spent in an underground prison without ever coming out.
When I came back, people started throwing sand at my body.
I told them that instead of allowing them to pour sand on me,
I would hug them to let them know that I was not a spirit.
As for my wife, she could not wait for many any longer because she thought that I was dead,
likewise others.
She told me she had gotten married to another man.
When I enquired about my son, she told me that he had already died one or two years ago.
I came back to The SCOAN to share my feelings with the man of God.
This is my friend. We are staying in the same compound.
I don't have anything bad in mind.
I just want everybody to know that I have forgiven my wife and everybody.
The only thing that is my joy is that I came out to see a free world. I can turn around, I can look,
I can run, I can buy any food I want to eat. I thank God for everything.
This is my friend.
This is my friend that got married to my wife.
Look at the screen of your television. This was exactly last week
when they came in their numbers - about 126 of them. They were deported from Libya.
He was among those that were deported. They made their way to The SCOAN right from the airport.
When they arrived at The SCOAN premises,
the man of God was moved with compassion and mercy,
in conjunction with Emmanuel TV Partners all over the world,
and they were all blessed with the cash sum of 7 million naira and two bags of rice for each person.
They were strictly advised to go back to their various homes and visit their family members
because their family members were expecting them back home.
We can see them when they came to The SCOAN -
helplessly because they were deported with nothing; they were frustrated.
When they came, they were helped at The SCOAN.
After they were blessed with the sum of 7 million naira and two bags of rice for each person,
they were advised to go back home and pay their family members a visit.
That was how he went back to his residence, where he was living,
the very home he left when he travelled to Libya five years ago.
But unfortunately for him, the wife made him to understand that
they thought he was dead because the news that came to her was that the husband was dead.
And unfortunately for him, the very son he left behind was already dead.
So the wife had no choice but to get married to the very friend he loves so much.
And that is the friend that is standing by him right now.
As you can see on the screen of your television,
the very brother who shared his experience a moment ago
was among the 126 Libyan deportees that visited The SCOAN last week.
They were blessed with the sum of 7 million, as you can see them there.
They were so excited that they were blessed with 7 million and two bags of rice each.
They were advised to go back home and visit their family members.
We also want to bring it to your hearing
that this very group has not been the only group that had been coming.
Ever since this year, they have been turning up in their numbers.
The moment they are deported, they find their way to The SCOAN for refuge.
Of course, this is the house of God.
The Bible says we should be a father to the fatherless and a benefactor to the needy.
That is what The SCOAN has been established for and that is what we are living for.
Right from the airport, they made their way to The SCOAN and they were blessed.
Let's put our hands together beautifully for the miracle-working God!
Now, as he made us to understand, he visited his house.
On getting there - the wife thought he was dead
and she got married to his closest friend who is standing by him here.
And the son he left behind is already dead.
But we have to understand one thing: His friend came here, simply because he heard
how the man of God had been helping people who were deported.
He is a very good friend of his. And when he learnt that the man of God helped his closest friend,
after he was deported with nothing from Libya, with a certain amount of money and two bags of rice,
he said he has to join him to The SCOAN to give thanks to God
and receive prayer for his own blessing as well.
Let's clap for Jesus Christ for them!
So, let's hear from his friend.
My name is Sulaimon Abolaji.
I am here because of my friend. We all live together in Ejigbo.
We heard that he had already died.
I took over taking care of his wife when he left.
After waiting a long time without seeing him,
with the information we had that he was already dead, I got married to his wife.
We were surprised when we saw him.
I was among those who poured sand on him, asking him if he was still alive.
But we thank God.
He is my best friend.
Due to what happened, we sat down, talked and reasoned together.
The main thing that brought me here is that when he explained to me that it was The SCOAN
that assisted him - he explained the whole story to me
and I had been hearing a lot of things about The SCOAN.
I have a friend who is a muslim who works with the ministry
because he knows that the man of God (T.B. Joshua) does not discriminate -
he does not look at tribe or religion. I also heard the same thing from my friend.
That is why I deemed it fit to come here.
If only the whole of Nigeria is watching and can emulate what Prophet T.B. Joshua has been doing
in our country, I think things would be better than they are.
That is why I came.
That is not enough for Jesus Christ!
Put your hands together beautifully for the miracle-working God!
All I want is for him to forgive and forget everything that has happened.
That is how God wants it and I still love him as a friend.
That is why I deemed it fit to come down to this place to rejoice with him.
Let's clap for wonderful Jesus Christ!
STANDARD FOR LIFE
We have of the man of God Prophet T.B. Joshua and Emmanuel TV Partners all over the world -
the man of God Prophet T.B. Joshua said we should give you the sum of 120,000 naira
for you to start your life anew and also two bags of rice.
I thank the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua, for blessing me with the sum of 120,000 naira
to start a new life in my village.
I thank the Emmanuel TV Partners all over the world too for blessing me with the sum of 120,000 naira
and two bags of rice to start a new life. I thank God for them.
Thank You, Jesus!
Mr Harrison Receives Cash Gift Of 120,000 Naira
From T.B. Joshua & Emmanuel TV Partners
Brother, we thank God Almighty for what He has done in your life,
for blessing you with the sum of 120,000 naira and two bags of rice for you to start a new life.
We want to use this opportunity to also advise you.
As much as the man of God Prophet T.B. Joshua and Emmanuel TV Partners all over the world
have blessed you with the sum of 120,000 naira and two bags of rice for you to start a new life,
make sure you go and maintain your relationship with Jesus Christ
and we pray you apply this, in Jesus' name.
Amen.
Finally, what word of advice do you have for everyone that is listening to you?
I advise everybody who is listening to me and this programme to be patient and wait for God's time
because God's time is the best. You should not be in a hurry in this life.
Amen. We believe everyone has listened to your word of advice
and as you go and maintain your relationship with Jesus Christ,
we pray that the Lord Jesus Christ will multiply this gift, in Jesus' name.
Amen! Thank you.
Thank You, Jesus!